uh hello
so today
I'll be demonstrating how we began
building our 3D space shooter game called rockfall
using unity
in the space we focused on creating the project
importing assets building the spaceship
setting up the camera follow system
placing the space station
adding the skybox
and preparing the UI canvas for future controls
ah so let's begin
first we open uh
Unity Hub and create a new project named Rockfall Game
with a 3D template
when the project loaded
we immediately saved the scene as main
as main as you can see inside the asset folder
uh next
we imported the unity package containing the 3d models
textures sounds
and other resources needed for the game
so after importing the assets
we started building our first game object
named the spaceship
or sheep
we went uh we renamed it renamed it as sheep
then from the models folder we drag
the ship model under the ship object
which made it a child
we renamed this child
object graphics
we reset the graphics object position
so it aligned perfectly with the invisible
parent ship object
uh next we wanted the camera to follow
to follow the ship smoothly
rather than being parented directly to it
we added a new script to the main camera called Smooth
Follow that CS
this script calculates a position behind
behind and above the spaceship
then
smoothly interpolates the camera toward that position
every frame
we assigned the ship object to
the scripts
target field and adjusted values like height
distance and damping
when we tested the game the camera
followed the ship smoothly with a natural delay
making the gameplay
gameplay feel more dynamic and realistic
next we place the space station
with which the player will protect later in the game
we created another empty game object
named Space Station
we reset the model's position so it aligned properly
we checked the station model
and confirmed that it already contained mesh colliders
uh which were automatically
generated when importing the asset
so to make the game feel like outer space
we replace Unity's default Skybox with our space Skybox
we created a new material name Skybox
and change it shader to Skybox 6 sided
then we assign the six texture
ah images to their correct sides front back
left right and up and down
finally we open up the lighting settings
and assign this Skybox material
the environment instantly looked like deep space
and the objects even received a green tint
based on their reflections on the sky
so for the last step in this space uh
space was setting up the UI canvas for controls
ah we created a canvas
which automatically generated an event system
we changed the canvas render mode to screen
space camera
uh
assign the main camera and set the plane distance to 1
we also change uh UA scale mode mode
to scale with screen size
and set the reference resolution to
1280 X 7 20
which is ideal for mobile controls
this canvas will later hold on
hold the on screen joystick
and fire button for controlling the ship
and that completes the first development stage
for a space shooter game Rockford
now I'll be demonstrating on how
it works in mobile app
so start we start a new game
these are the controls
a pause button
and
so for the
space station it's right there
and the asteroids are going straight at it
so you can shoot at it
so that's it for the rockfall game